Guide to the Kenneth G. Wilson papers, 1960-2000.
Wilson, Kenneth G. papers
- Series VII. Materials on Supercomputing and the Cornell Supercomputing Theory Center
  - Drafts for Articles on Supercomputing, c. 1983 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Mostly undated; "Planning for the Future of U.S. Scientific and Engineering Computing", "Theoretical Science and Computer Technology", "Supercomputers: Market Size and Market Risk", "Role and Needs for Large Scale Computing for Theoretical Physics", "The Computerization of Science" (c. 1983), "Present vs. Future Supercomputers", "Supercomputers", "Theoretical Science in the Coming Decades", "DD Seminar: Theoretical Science and the Future of Large Scale Computing", "Supercomputers, Science, and the American Spirit", Ken Wilson's talk: "Questions and Answers", Topics for Talk by K. Wilson at Los Alamos Panel (1983)
  - Formal Reports and Congressional Testimony, 1981-1989 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    Memorandum to "Present and Potential Supercomputer Users" (April, 1981), Memorandum to "Users fo Large-Scale Computing in Government, Industry, and Universities" (July 15, 1981)(2 copies), "Supercomputers -- outline for presentation at meeting of Business-Higher Education Forum" (Jan. 22, 1983), letter to J. D. Kuehler, Sr. VP of IBM (April 9, 1984), presentation at the Truman Centennial (1984), testimony at the Supercomputer hearing of the House Science and Technology Committee (Tallahassie, August, 1985), transcript of the AFIPS 25th anniversary Policy Symposium (May, 1986), Meeting the Grand Challenges of Science at the National Supercomputer Centers, meeting of the center directors (at the NSF?) (February, 1987), White Paper on Advanced Computation and Simulation of Complex Material Phenomena (February, 1987), testimony before the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology (March, 1988), presentation to the National Governors' Association Working Group on State Initiatives in Applied Research (Washington, April, 1988), transcript of the executive seminar on Supercomputing for the Future of the United States (Boston University, June, 1989), transcript of a panel: Fiber Optics, an Important tool (undated; includes Gov. Mario Cuomo)
  - The National Science Foundation in the 1990's, July 1988 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    Pamphlet, reprints, and associated correspondence
  - Cornell Theory Center Documents (Box 6, Folder 5)
    Cornell Theory Center grant proposals and supporting documents
  - Cornell Theory Center Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 6)
    Correspondence associated with the Cornell Theory Center
  - Cornell Theory Center News Articles and Interviews (Box 6, Folder 7)
    News clippings and interviews related to supercomputing
  - Raw Notes (Box 6, Folder 8)
    Raw notes for articles on supercomputing
  - Slides (Box 6, Folder 9)
    Transparencies of talks on supercomputing and the Theory Center
  - Correspondence Related to Supercomputing (Box 6, Folder 10)
    Mainly invitations to conferences
  - Theory Center Printed Materials, c. 1989 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    Issues of Forefronts, the Theory Center newsletter Science and Supercomputing (glossy brochure, 1989)
  - Supercomputing Reports by Others (Box 6, Folder 12)
    Miscellaneous reports relevant to supercomputing
  - Technical Materials from the Theory Center (Box 6, Folder 13)
    T-series users guide (preliminary) - Floating Point Systems, tutorial introduction to Trillium for C Programmers - M. Braner, an application for the T-20: a vector interpreter - D. Bergmark
  - Gibbs Project Documentation (Box 6, Folder 14)
    Gibbs project proposal, K. G. Wilson, D. Gries, and A. Grimison, addendum by K. G. Wilson, GIBBS: a Proposed Scientific Program Development System, K. G. Wilson, GIBBS -- Operational Description, K. G. Wilson and W. Wenzel
- Series VIII. Materials on Education Reform
  - A National Plan for Education Reform (Box 7, Folder 4)
    Report, correspondence and responses
  - Drafts of Papers on Education Reform (Box 7, Folder 5)
    "Industrial Redesign", "Achieving Education Reform" (op. ed. piece) (2 copies), "Diagnosing Productivity Problems", "K-12 Scientific Literacy: a Plan for Ohio State University and the State of Ohio" (August 1989), "A Cognitive Studies/Teacher Enhancement Program at Ohio State University" (several stages of drafts), "Innovation and Basic Research: the Key to Achieving National Education Goals", "Briefing Paper: Achieving the National Goals for Education", "Operation Horace Mann", "Achieving Education Reform"
  - Rough Drafts and Raw Notes on Education Reform (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Discovery Project (Box 7, Folder 7)
    Discovery Project: Proposal to the National Science Foundation, materials and correspondence related to the Discovery Project
  - Ohio State Education Proposals (Box 7, Folder 8)
    Ohio State interdisciplinary seed grant proposal: "Cooperative Inquiry with Diversified Learning Teams Engaged in Systemic Education Reform", Preliminary Proposal to the NSF: "A Cognitive Studies/Teacher Enhancement Program at Ohio State University", related correspondence
  - Material for "Redesigning Education" (Box 7, Folder 9)
    Chapter summaries for the book proposal (Ben Daviss), rough drafts
  - On Peter Drucker's School Reform Proposals (Box 7, Folder 10)
    Drucker on Education: "Does Drucker have the best ideas for school reform?" (March 2006) "A New Strategy for Education Reform, Starting with a Skunk Works", "Reviving Drucker's Research Discipline of Social Ecology" (December 2007) (drafts - K. G. Wilson and C. Barsky)
  - Substantive Correspondence on Education Issues (Box 7, Folder 11)
    Exchange of letters, and related materials to/from: Arnold Arons (University of Washington), Lewis Branscomb (J. F. Kennedy School, Harvard), Urie Bronfbrenner (Cornell), Harvey Brooks (J. F. Kennedy School, Harvard), S. Cecchetti, Paul David (Stanford), Julie Dougherty, Louis Gerstner (Chairman and CEO, IBM), Z. Golab-Meyer (Jagiellonian University, Krakow), Kurt Gottfried (Cornell), Dee Hock (CEO emeritus, VISA), Paul Kennedy (Yale), Jack Keuhler (Vice Charman, IBM), Leon Lederman (Director emeritus, Fermilab), Mervin Muller (Ohio State), Sharon Porter Robinson (COO, Educational Testing Service), Seymour Sarason (Yale), Dick and Iris Schutz, Robert Slavin (Johns Hopkins), W. Rodman Snelling, Karim Joseph Mourad (Ohio State), John Staudenmaier (University of Detroit Mercy), Carl Wieman (University of Colorado; now at Stanford), Alexandra Wigdor (National Research Council), William Wulf (National Academy of Engineering)
  - Less Substantive Correspondence Related to Education (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Letters of Recommendation and Evaluation - Physics Education (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence from Ohio State (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - ARTE Draft Proposal, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    ARTE (Association for the Recognition of Talent in Education)
  - Ohio Science and Technology Commission, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    Materials for the Human Resources Subcommittee
  - Correspondence with the National Science Foundation (NSF), the National Research Council (NRC), and the National Education Association (NEA) (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Slides from Wilson's Presentations (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Materials by Others on Science Education (Box 7, Folder 19)